<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ukraine Has Launched New Push in South &#8211; Methodik Acuitybrands</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/ukraine-has-launched-new-push-in-south/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 18:22:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/live-favicon.jpg</url>
	<title>Ukraine Has Launched New Push in South &#8211; Methodik Acuitybrands</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Russian Officials Say Ukraine Has Launched New Push in South</title>
		<link>/russian-officials-say-ukraine-has-launched-new-push-in-south/</link>
					<comments>/russian-officials-say-ukraine-has-launched-new-push-in-south/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 14:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukraine Has Launched New Push in South]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ukrainian forces launched a “massive” attack south of the town of Orikhiv in the Zaporizhzhia region, Russia’s Defense Ministry said on Wednesday, suggesting that a new phase of Kyiv’s southern counteroffensive may be underway. Ukraine deployed three battalions reinforced with...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Ukrainian forces launched a “massive” attack south of the town of Orikhiv in the Zaporizhzhia region, Russia’s Defense Ministry said on Wednesday, suggesting that a new phase of Kyiv’s southern counteroffensive may be underway. Ukraine deployed three battalions reinforced with tanks, said Igor Konashenkov, the Russian Defense Ministry’s chief spokesman, but he added that the attack and a second one near Robotyne, a Russian-held frontline village around eight miles southeast of Orikhiv, had been repelled.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Mr. Konashenkov’s comments, reported by the Russian state news agency Tass, could not be independently confirmed, and Ukrainian officials did not directly comment. But the area south of Orikhiv, a town that Ukraine holds, is a key battleground in its push to expel Russian forces from the south and east of the country, and both sides have built up their forces in the area. Vladimir Rogov, an official appointed by Moscow in southern Ukraine, said on the Telegram app that fierce battles had begun south of Orikhiv, involving Ukrainian troops who had been trained abroad and were equipped with about 100 German-made Leopard tanks and American-made Bradley Fighting Vehicles.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>A Russian occupation official said Ukrainian forces equipped with Western weapons had begun a significant attack in the Zaporizhzhia region.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Here’s what we’re covering:</strong><br />
The area south of Orikhiv is a key battleground in Ukraine’s counteroffensive.<br />
British military intelligence says Russia plans to enforce a blockade against Ukraine.<br />
The U.N. Security Council is meeting as Russian attacks on Odesa have escalated.<br />
Internet trolls propelled Prigozhin’s rise. Now some celebrate his fall.<br />
A former U.S. Marine freed in a prisoner swap was injured while fighting in Ukraine.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Another Russian occupation official in Zaporizhzhia, Yevgeny Balitsky, said that Ukraine had made 36 attempts to shell settlements in the region since Tuesday. He said that Moscow’s forces had rebuffed Ukrainian attempts to break through Russian defenses. The Ukrainian military’s general staff said in its daily update on Wednesday that Russian forces were engaged in defensive operations in the Zaporizhzhia region. A spokesman for the general staff, Andriy Kovalev, said that Russian forces had unsuccessfully tried to restore lost positions northeast of Robotyne. “The enemy continues to put up strong resistance, moves units, and actively uses reserves,” he said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">President Volodymyr Zelensky of Ukraine said that he had met with Gen. Valery Zaluzhny, the commander of Ukraine’s armed forces, and discussed offensive and defensive fighting on the front line. “We believe in our boys,” Mr. Zelensky said on Telegram, giving no details of military operations. “We continue to work.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ukraine’s counteroffensive, launched last month and conducted along three axes including in the western part of Zaporizhzhia region, has moved more slowly than some military experts and Western allies had expected. In part, this is because of dense Russian minefields, which have impeded Ukraine’s advances, but also because of the strong resistance of Russian forces who have had months to prepare.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In addition, Ukraine had not yet sent into battle many of its Western-trained troops or the latest vehicles supplied by allies, according to U.S. officials. Ukraine’s overall objective on the southern front is to reach the Sea of Azov, which is about 60 miles south of Orikhiv. Doing so would cut off the so-called land bridge connecting Russian occupation forces in southern Ukraine from those in the east.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/russian-officials-say-ukraine-has-launched-new-push-in-south/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
