<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Methodik Acuitybrands</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 18:23:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/live-favicon.jpg</url>
	<title>Methodik Acuitybrands</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>UN Rights Chief Urges Probe Over Israel&#8217;s Gaza Bombardment</title>
		<link>/un-rights-chief-urges-probe-over-israels-gaza-bombardment/</link>
					<comments>/un-rights-chief-urges-probe-over-israels-gaza-bombardment/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Rights Chief Urges Probe Over Israel's Gaza Bombardment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UN human rights chief on Friday urged an investigation into what he called Israel&#8217;s use of &#8220;high-impact explosive weapons&#8221; in Gaza, which he said was causing indiscriminate destruction in the besieged Palestinian enclave. Volker Turk, the UN High Commissioner...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The UN human rights chief on Friday urged an investigation into what he called Israel&#8217;s use of &#8220;high-impact explosive weapons&#8221; in Gaza, which he said was causing indiscriminate destruction in the besieged Palestinian enclave. Volker Turk, the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights, said Israel must end its use of such weapons in the densely populated area, home to 2.3 million Palestinians, half of whom have been displaced by fighting in the last month. Turk was not specific about what weapons he was referring to. Asked for comment, the Israeli military said it was making checks and would respond later.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Israel&#8217;s air, sea and land bombardment of Gaza, accompanied now by a ground assault deep inside the territory, aims to destroy the militant group Hamas which controls Gaza. Hamas killed 1,400 Israelis in a cross-border Oct. 7 attack, according to Israeli tallies, and the U.N. has said the assault involved war crimes. Israel&#8217;s subsequent bombardment of Gaza has killed more than 10,000 Palestinians according to health authorities in the Palestinian enclave. The extensive Israeli bombardment of Gaza, including the use of high-impact explosive weapons in densely populated areas is clearly having a devastating humanitarian and human rights impact, Turk told a news conference during a visit to Jordan&#8217;s capital Amman.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The attacks must be investigated, We have very serious concerns that these amount to disproportionate attacks in breach of international humanitarian law. Israel blames Hamas for civilian deaths in Gaza, saying the group uses the population as human shields and hides weapons and equipment around hospitals, which have been hit by bombardments. Any use by Palestinian armed groups of civilians and civilian objects to shield themselves from attack is in contravention of the laws of war, Turk said. &#8220;But such conduct by Palestinian armed groups does not absolve Israel of its obligation to ensure that civilians are spared. Turk also said Israel must take immediate measures to protect Palestinians in the occupied West Bank, where violence is escalating between Palestinians and Israeli soldiers and settlers.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Turk said at least 176 Palestinians, including 43 children and one woman, had been killed in incidents involving Israeli security forces since the beginning of October. At least eight Palestinians had been killed by Israeli settlers. Israel has vowed to destroy Hamas and said it has also been conducting counter-terrorism operations against militants from the group and other Palestinian armed factions in the West Bank. Over the past 18 months, Israeli troops have killed hundreds of Palestinians &#8211; hardened militant fighters, stone-throwing youths and uninvolved civilians &#8211; and made thousands of arrests across the West Bank. In the same period, dozens of Israelis have been killed in attacks by Palestinians.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/un-rights-chief-urges-probe-over-israels-gaza-bombardment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Neel Joler Kabbyo’ Trailer to Release This Week</title>
		<link>/neel-joler-kabbyo-trailer-to-release-this-week/</link>
					<comments>/neel-joler-kabbyo-trailer-to-release-this-week/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 21:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neel Joler Kabbyo Trailer to Release This Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trailer to Release This Week]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The much-anticipated trailer of Nisho, Mehazabien starrer &#8220;Neel Joler Kabbyo&#8221; is set to release on Thursday. The Shihab Shaheen directorial web-film is scheduled to be released on the popular OTT platform iScreen on November 16. Poster of the film After...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The much-anticipated trailer of Nisho, Mehazabien starrer &#8220;Neel Joler Kabbyo&#8221; is set to release on Thursday. The Shihab Shaheen directorial web-film is scheduled to be released on the popular OTT platform iScreen on November 16.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Poster of the film</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">After the immense success of the web-film &#8220;Redrum&#8221;, the Afran Nisho and Mehazabien Chowdhury duo were not seen in any OTT content together. They will however come together for this web-film by Shihab Shaheen. The platform had already revealed the first poster of the film on November 1, on their social media. The poster shows Mehazabien and Nisho standing by the seashore, holding hands, during the twilight hours. Confirming the release, director Shihab Shaheen said, &#8220;The audience will get to see a fantastic story in this film. Besides, Nisho and Mehazabien have a dedicated fan base. I believe that even the general audience will enjoy the content.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>I want to compete with none but myself: Tania Brishty</strong><br />
&#8220;The web-film will center around one of its protagonists – a girl&#8217;s fascination for the sea. When we were shooting this, OTT platforms were not popular. During and post-pandemic it had and has been rising in demand. Also, we had to cancel the shooting of this project four times. Later, this web-film was produced for iScreen,&#8221; the director further added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/neel-joler-kabbyo-trailer-to-release-this-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shakira Charged With Tax Evasion in Spain For a Second Time</title>
		<link>/shakira-charged-with-tax-evasion-in-spain-for-a-second-time/</link>
					<comments>/shakira-charged-with-tax-evasion-in-spain-for-a-second-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 11:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shakira Charged With Tax Evasion in Spain For a Second Time]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A Spanish prosecutor has lodged a second tax claim against Colombian singer Shakira, accusing her of defrauding the state of 6.6 million euros ($7.0 million) in 2018, according to a request to the investigating court seen by Reuters on Tuesday....]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">A Spanish prosecutor has lodged a second tax claim against Colombian singer Shakira, accusing her of defrauding the state of 6.6 million euros ($7.0 million) in 2018, according to a request to the investigating court seen by Reuters on Tuesday. Known as the Queen of Latin Pop, Shakira has opted to go to trial in November in Barcelona in a case where she denies failing to pay 14.5 million euros in tax for the period 2012-14, for which she could be jailed for up to eight years In the new case, the prosecutor alleges that in 2018, Shakira failed to declare profits of $12.5 million from an advance payment for her El Dorado World Tour concert, among others.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">At that time, she was in a relationship with FC Barcelona soccer star Gerard Pique and living in the city with their two children. Pop star Shakira may get 8 years in Spanish jail for tax evasion Prosecutors argue that she was resident in Spain and so required to tax all her worldwide revenues there, no matter where they were earned. Instead, they say, she diverted money to &#8220;companies domiciled in countries with low taxation and high opacity&#8221;. The 46-year-old, who has sold millions of records worldwide, is accused of failing to pay 5.4 million euros in income tax, and is calculated to owe 6.0 million after taking into account accrued interest but also voluntary payments.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">She is also accused of defrauding the state of 773,600 euros in wealth tax, resulting in a debt of 625,190 euros. Shakira&#8217;s legal team said she had not received any notification of the new case in Miami, where she is now based. &#8220;Shakira&#8217;s legal team is focused on preparing for the trial for the 2012-14 fiscal years, which will begin on Nov. 20,&#8221; it said in an emailed statement. The singer turned down a deal with prosecutors in the 2012-14 case, saying she was confident that she had behaved correctly and transparently from the beginning.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/shakira-charged-with-tax-evasion-in-spain-for-a-second-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Drone’s View Behind Russian Lines Cratered Fields and Charred Armor</title>
		<link>/a-drones-view-behind-russian-lines-cratered-fields-and-charred-armor/</link>
					<comments>/a-drones-view-behind-russian-lines-cratered-fields-and-charred-armor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 15:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cratered Fields and Charred Armor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The images a reconnaissance drone sent back to Ukrainian forces provided a vivid portrait of the Russian side of the war zone. Damaged houses gave way to cratered fields on Ukraine’s southern steppe. There was burned-out armor in a scorched...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The images a reconnaissance drone sent back to Ukrainian forces provided a vivid portrait of the Russian side of the war zone. Damaged houses gave way to cratered fields on Ukraine’s southern steppe. There was burned-out armor in a scorched forest. A jagged Russian trench along a tree line had been blasted by American-supplied cluster munitions barely a week earlier, according to Lt. Ashot Arutiunian, the commander of the unit that recorded the images.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">He pointed to holes in the roofs of several large agricultural buildings in a village and said they had most likely been hit by the American-made HIMARS rocket system; it is known for its accuracy, and there was no damage to surrounding buildings or to a nearby church. This was on a recent morning, with Ukrainian artillery firing relentlessly, the deep rumbling explosions of the impact resonating in the distance. Mixed in were the louder explosions of Russian shells landing on Ukrainian positions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">But Lieutenant Arutiunian was focused on the skies above. Drones have become a mainstay used by both Russian and Ukrainian forces, reconnoitering the battlefield and directing fire against enemy targets. Lieutenant Arutiunian, who uses the military call sign Doc — a reference to the doctorate in data mining he holds from Kyiv Polytechnic — commands four teams in the unmanned aerial vehicle service of the Ukrainian Volunteer Army, operating on the southern front. They deploy a variety of propeller-driven drones and planes to track Russian forces for the Ukrainian military and are constantly adjusting tactics and equipment to evade Russian interceptors.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This week, one of the units allowed a team of New York Times journalists to accompany it on a mission close to the front line as it sent a drone into Russian-occupied territory to surveil the battlefront. A condition was that the unit’s precise location could not be reported. Amid a background of artillery fire, the team got to work under cover of a small copse of trees, unpacking equipment and setting up four antennas; those were needed to work round the threats of both Russian and Ukrainian electronic jammers that can swiftly end the flight of a drone.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The fixed wing craft the unit’s members were using was equipped with two cameras and an independent global positioning system as backup, to give the pilot several options to bring it home should one or more of the systems fail. In this reconnaissance mission we are investigating the terrain, Lieutenant Arutiunian said. Later, back at base, they would examine the video footage on a big monitor to try to spot Russian military, he said: “We are looking for soldiers, warehouses, gasoline depots, whatever.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/a-drones-view-behind-russian-lines-cratered-fields-and-charred-armor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Officials Say Ukraine Has Launched New Push in South</title>
		<link>/russian-officials-say-ukraine-has-launched-new-push-in-south/</link>
					<comments>/russian-officials-say-ukraine-has-launched-new-push-in-south/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 14:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukraine Has Launched New Push in South]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ukrainian forces launched a “massive” attack south of the town of Orikhiv in the Zaporizhzhia region, Russia’s Defense Ministry said on Wednesday, suggesting that a new phase of Kyiv’s southern counteroffensive may be underway. Ukraine deployed three battalions reinforced with...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Ukrainian forces launched a “massive” attack south of the town of Orikhiv in the Zaporizhzhia region, Russia’s Defense Ministry said on Wednesday, suggesting that a new phase of Kyiv’s southern counteroffensive may be underway. Ukraine deployed three battalions reinforced with tanks, said Igor Konashenkov, the Russian Defense Ministry’s chief spokesman, but he added that the attack and a second one near Robotyne, a Russian-held frontline village around eight miles southeast of Orikhiv, had been repelled.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Mr. Konashenkov’s comments, reported by the Russian state news agency Tass, could not be independently confirmed, and Ukrainian officials did not directly comment. But the area south of Orikhiv, a town that Ukraine holds, is a key battleground in its push to expel Russian forces from the south and east of the country, and both sides have built up their forces in the area. Vladimir Rogov, an official appointed by Moscow in southern Ukraine, said on the Telegram app that fierce battles had begun south of Orikhiv, involving Ukrainian troops who had been trained abroad and were equipped with about 100 German-made Leopard tanks and American-made Bradley Fighting Vehicles.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>A Russian occupation official said Ukrainian forces equipped with Western weapons had begun a significant attack in the Zaporizhzhia region.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Here’s what we’re covering:</strong><br />
The area south of Orikhiv is a key battleground in Ukraine’s counteroffensive.<br />
British military intelligence says Russia plans to enforce a blockade against Ukraine.<br />
The U.N. Security Council is meeting as Russian attacks on Odesa have escalated.<br />
Internet trolls propelled Prigozhin’s rise. Now some celebrate his fall.<br />
A former U.S. Marine freed in a prisoner swap was injured while fighting in Ukraine.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Another Russian occupation official in Zaporizhzhia, Yevgeny Balitsky, said that Ukraine had made 36 attempts to shell settlements in the region since Tuesday. He said that Moscow’s forces had rebuffed Ukrainian attempts to break through Russian defenses. The Ukrainian military’s general staff said in its daily update on Wednesday that Russian forces were engaged in defensive operations in the Zaporizhzhia region. A spokesman for the general staff, Andriy Kovalev, said that Russian forces had unsuccessfully tried to restore lost positions northeast of Robotyne. “The enemy continues to put up strong resistance, moves units, and actively uses reserves,” he said.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">President Volodymyr Zelensky of Ukraine said that he had met with Gen. Valery Zaluzhny, the commander of Ukraine’s armed forces, and discussed offensive and defensive fighting on the front line. “We believe in our boys,” Mr. Zelensky said on Telegram, giving no details of military operations. “We continue to work.”</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Ukraine’s counteroffensive, launched last month and conducted along three axes including in the western part of Zaporizhzhia region, has moved more slowly than some military experts and Western allies had expected. In part, this is because of dense Russian minefields, which have impeded Ukraine’s advances, but also because of the strong resistance of Russian forces who have had months to prepare.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In addition, Ukraine had not yet sent into battle many of its Western-trained troops or the latest vehicles supplied by allies, according to U.S. officials. Ukraine’s overall objective on the southern front is to reach the Sea of Azov, which is about 60 miles south of Orikhiv. Doing so would cut off the so-called land bridge connecting Russian occupation forces in southern Ukraine from those in the east.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/russian-officials-say-ukraine-has-launched-new-push-in-south/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
